<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tax Data | Corbin Miller</title>
    <link>https://corbinmiller.website/tags/tax-data/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://corbinmiller.website/tags/tax-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Tax Data</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 16:04:42 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://corbinmiller.website/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Tax Data</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/tags/tax-data/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employer-Sponsored Health Insurance Premiums and Income in US Tax Data</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/project/premiums/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 16:04:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://corbinmiller.website/project/premiums/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Currently available survey data does not capture important information about the distribution of employer-sponsored health insurance premiums in the US. We provide new evidence, based on administrative tax data, about the relationship of premiums to individual characteristics such as income. First, we demonstrate that premiums measured in the tax data are comparable to what we know from survey data. Then we show that those with higher incomes have more expensive policies. In fact, those in the top 10 percent of the income distribution account for 21 percent of total premiums. Even with these disparities, there is substantially less inequality in spending on ESI than in income overall.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employers and Disability Insurance: Evidence from Individual Tax Returns</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/project/employers_di/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 16:40:48 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://corbinmiller.website/project/employers_di/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we provide new evidence on the distribution of claims in the Social Security Disability Insurance (SSDI) program across employers and industries. We also relate SSDI claims to employer and employee wage premiums and discuss implications for measures of inequality. Our research makes use of the universe of individual tax returns for the period 2000-2018, which allows to develop measures of the incidence of SSDI claims for all U.S. firms and industries. We have two main findings. First, we find that there is substantial variation in SSDI claiming rates across firms and industries. Second, we find that there is a negative association between firm wage premiums and SSDI claiming rates.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
