<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Health | Corbin Miller</title>
    <link>https://corbinmiller.website/categories/health/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://corbinmiller.website/categories/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Health</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2019</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 16:04:42 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://corbinmiller.website/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Health</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/categories/health/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Distribution of Employer-Sponsored Health Insurance Premiums</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/project/premiums/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 16:04:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://corbinmiller.website/project/premiums/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rapid increases in employer-sponsored health insurance premiums are a growing concern for policymakers. Given this concern, it is important to understand how these premium costs are distributed across employees. We use newly available tax data to shed light on the distribution. More specifically, employers with more than 250 employees are required to report the total premiums paid by both employers and employees to the IRS on Form W-2. We are the first to use employer-employee-linked administrative data to measure the distribution and correlates of health insurance premiums in the United States. In particular, we link premium information from Code DD on Form W-2 with information from Forms 1095-B and 1095-C. Combining the total premium information with months and type of coverage allows us to calculate an annualized premium comparable to survey data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Interactions and Smoking Initiation</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/project/intergen_smoking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 15:44:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://corbinmiller.website/project/intergen_smoking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper explores the role of social interactions on a youth&amp;rsquo;s decision to begin smoking. Specifically, we estimate the effect of cigarette taxes during early childhood on beginning smoking later in adolescence in a discrete-time hazard model. These taxes do not directly affect children but may change the prevalence of smoking among parents, older relatives, or other adults. We find that a $0.25 cigarette tax increase during childhood decreases smoking initiation by 12.5 percent. Our results suggest that parents and older siblings do not account for the entire intergenerational effect, so other members of the community also likely play a role. Prior work understates the total effect of cigarette taxes by not considering this indirect channel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employers and Disability Insurance: Evidence from Individual Tax Returns</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/project/employers_di/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 16:40:48 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://corbinmiller.website/project/employers_di/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we provide new evidence on the distribution of claims in the Social Security Disability Insurance (SSDI) program across employers and industries.
We also relate SSDI claims to employer and employee wage premiums and discuss implications for measures of inequality.
Our research makes use of the universe of individual tax returns for the period 2000-2018, which allows to develop measures of the incidence of SSDI claims for all U.S. firms and industries.
We have two main findings.
First, we find that there is substantial variation in SSDI claiming rates across firms and industries.
Second, we find that there is a negative association between firm wage premiums and SSDI claiming rates.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
