<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Corbin Miller</title>
    <link>https://corbinmiller.website/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://corbinmiller.website/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 16:40:48 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://corbinmiller.website/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does School Spending Pay For Itself? Long-run Effects on Personal Income</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/project/school_spending/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 16:40:48 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://corbinmiller.website/project/school_spending/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past half-century, court-ordered increases in public school spending dramatically changed the level and distribution of school resources in the United States. Recent evidence from surveys suggests that school finance reforms improved students’ short- and long-run outcomes. However, the policy implications remain unclear because, although observed effects are significantly different from zero, we do not know whether the benefits exceed the costs, or whether the internal rate of return exceeds benchmark interest rates. This paper seeks to improve on past cost-benefit estimates by using population-scale longitudinal administrative tax data, which allow us to: (1) measure effects on lifecycle income, with age-specific estimates for each age from 14 to 34, each based on the outcomes for 21 birth cohorts (from 1965-2006); (2) correct for family unobservables and migration that may bias estimates upwards; and (3) correct for mis-measurement of childhood exposures that may bias estimates downwards. We build on past work using reforms to instrument for school spending, and thus provide an independent check on those crucial estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employers and Disability Insurance: Evidence from Individual Tax Returns</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/project/employers_di/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 16:40:48 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://corbinmiller.website/project/employers_di/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we provide new evidence on the distribution of claims in the Social Security Disability Insurance (SSDI) program across employers and industries. We also relate SSDI claims to employer and employee wage premiums and discuss implications for measures of inequality. Our research makes use of the universe of individual tax returns for the period 2000-2018, which allows to develop measures of the incidence of SSDI claims for all U.S. firms and industries. We have two main findings. First, we find that there is substantial variation in SSDI claiming rates across firms and industries. Second, we find that there is a negative association between firm wage premiums and SSDI claiming rates.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Incidence of Flood Insurance</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/project/flood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 16:40:48 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://corbinmiller.website/project/flood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past half-century, court-ordered increases in public school spending dramatically changed the level and distribution of school resources in the United States. Recent evidence from surveys suggests that school finance reforms improved students’ short- and long-run outcomes. However, the policy implications remain unclear because, although observed effects are significantly different from zero, we do not know whether the benefits exceed the costs, or whether the internal rate of return exceeds benchmark interest rates. This paper seeks to improve on past cost-benefit estimates by using population-scale longitudinal administrative tax data, which allow us to: (1) measure effects on lifecycle income, with age-specific estimates for each age from 14 to 34, each based on the outcomes for 21 birth cohorts (from 1965-2006); (2) correct for family unobservables and migration that may bias estimates upwards; and (3) correct for mis-measurement of childhood exposures that may bias estimates downwards. We build on past work using reforms to instrument for school spending, and thus provide an independent check on those crucial estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
