<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Corbin Miller</title>
    <link>https://corbinmiller.website/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://corbinmiller.website/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 09:04:42 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://corbinmiller.website/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Army Service in the All-Volunteer Era</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/project/army/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 09:04:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://corbinmiller.website/project/army/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Revise &amp;amp; Resubmit, Quarterly Journal of Economics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the beginning of the all-volunteer era, millions of young Americans have chosen to enlist in the military. These volunteers disproportionately come from disadvantaged backgrounds, and while some aspects of military service are likely to be beneficial, exposure to violence and other elements of service could worsen outcomes. This paper links the universe of Army applicants between 1990 and 2011 to their federal tax records and other administrative data and uses two eligibility thresholds in the Armed Forces Qualifying Test (AFQT) in a regression discontinuity design to estimate the effects of Army enlistment on earnings and related outcomes. In the 19 years following application, Army service increases average annual earnings by over $4,000 at both cutoffs. However, whether service increases long-run earnings varies significantly by race. Black servicemembers experience annual gains of $5,500 to $15,000 11-19 years after applying while White servicemembers do not experience significant changes. By providing Black servicemembers a stable and well-paying Army job and by opening doors to higher-paid post-service employment, the Army significantly closes the Black-White earnings gap in our sample.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employer-Sponsored Health Insurance Premiums and Income in US Tax Data</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/project/premiums/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 16:04:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://corbinmiller.website/project/premiums/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Conditionally Accepted, Journal of Public Economics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The distribution of employer-sponsored health insurance premiums in the United States is difficult to fully characterize with survey data. Using administrative tax data, we plot the population distribution of premiums and provide new evidence about the relationship between premiums and demographic characteristics, such as income. First, we demonstrate that the distribution of premiums measured in the tax data is comparable to survey data. Then we leverage detailed individual-level information for the population of tax filers to show that those with higher incomes are more likely to have an employer-sponsored insurance (ESI) policy and, conditional on having a policy, select more expensive plans. In fact, those in the top 10 percent of the income distribution account for 21 percent of aggregate ESI premiums. Even with these disparities though, inequality in ESI spending is less than half of that in income overall.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Interactions and Smoking Initiation</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/project/intergen_smoking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 15:44:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://corbinmiller.website/project/intergen_smoking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper explores the role of social interactions on a youth&amp;rsquo;s decision to begin smoking. Specifically, we estimate the effect of cigarette taxes during early childhood on beginning smoking later in adolescence in a discrete-time hazard model. These taxes do not directly affect children but may change the prevalence of smoking among parents, older relatives, or other adults. We find that a $0.25 cigarette tax increase during childhood decreases smoking initiation by 12.5 percent. Our results suggest that parents and older siblings do not account for the entire indirect effect, so other members of the community also likely play a role. Prior work understates the total effect of cigarette taxes by not considering this indirect channel.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Effect of Education Spending on Student Achievement</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/project/jmp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 15:24:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://corbinmiller.website/project/jmp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Opportunities to estimate the causal effect of school spending on student achievement are infrequent and have been based, almost entirely, on variation in spending from large school finance reforms. 
Property values also affect school spending through both local property tax revenue and the level of state aid provided to each school district. 
However, little is known about the effect property values have on student achievement through their impact on school revenue. 
In this paper, I estimate the effect of education spending on district-level student outcomes in 24 states by leveraging changes in revenue driven by property value variation. 
I interact state-level changes in property values with fixed school finance formulas that measure how state aid and local revenue respond to those changes (the &amp;ldquo;wealth price&amp;rdquo;) to create a simulated instrument for school spending. 
By collecting administrative data on property values for over 7,000 school districts, I am able to measure a leave-one-out mean change in property values for school districts in each state. 
The instrument is highly predictive of changes in revenue and spending. 
My estimates suggest that a 10 percent increase in spending improves graduation rates by 3 to 5 percentage points and student test scores by 0.07 to 0.09 standard deviations. 
These results suggest that market variation in property values affects student outcomes through existing school finance formulas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does School Spending Pay For Itself? Long-run Effects on Personal Income</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/project/school_spending/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 16:40:48 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://corbinmiller.website/project/school_spending/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past half-century, court-ordered increases in public school spending dramatically changed the level and distribution of school resources in the United States. Recent evidence from surveys suggests that school finance reforms improved students’ short- and long-run outcomes. However, the policy implications remain unclear because, although observed effects are significantly different from zero, we do not know whether the benefits exceed the costs, or whether the internal rate of return exceeds benchmark interest rates. This paper seeks to improve on past cost-benefit estimates by using population-scale longitudinal administrative tax data, which allow us to: (1) measure effects on lifecycle income, with age-specific estimates for each age from 14 to 34, each based on the outcomes for 21 birth cohorts (from 1965-2006); (2) correct for family unobservables and migration that may bias estimates upwards; and (3) correct for mis-measurement of childhood exposures that may bias estimates downwards. We build on past work using reforms to instrument for school spending, and thus provide an independent check on those crucial estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employers and Disability Insurance: Evidence from Individual Tax Returns</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/project/employers_di/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 16:40:48 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://corbinmiller.website/project/employers_di/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we provide new evidence on the distribution of claims in the Social Security Disability Insurance (SSDI) program across employers and industries. We also relate SSDI claims to employer and employee wage premiums and discuss implications for measures of inequality. Our research makes use of the universe of individual tax returns for the period 2000-2018, which allows to develop measures of the incidence of SSDI claims for all U.S. firms and industries. We have two main findings. First, we find that there is substantial variation in SSDI claiming rates across firms and industries. Second, we find that there is a negative association between firm wage premiums and SSDI claiming rates.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Incidence of Flood Insurance</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/project/flood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 16:40:48 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://corbinmiller.website/project/flood/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past half-century, court-ordered increases in public school spending dramatically changed the level and distribution of school resources in the United States. Recent evidence from surveys suggests that school finance reforms improved students’ short- and long-run outcomes. However, the policy implications remain unclear because, although observed effects are significantly different from zero, we do not know whether the benefits exceed the costs, or whether the internal rate of return exceeds benchmark interest rates. This paper seeks to improve on past cost-benefit estimates by using population-scale longitudinal administrative tax data, which allow us to: (1) measure effects on lifecycle income, with age-specific estimates for each age from 14 to 34, each based on the outcomes for 21 birth cohorts (from 1965-2006); (2) correct for family unobservables and migration that may bias estimates upwards; and (3) correct for mis-measurement of childhood exposures that may bias estimates downwards. We build on past work using reforms to instrument for school spending, and thus provide an independent check on those crucial estimates.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rent-Seeking through Collective Bargaining</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/project/ohio_levies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 16:35:56 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://corbinmiller.website/project/ohio_levies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Economics of Education Review (2021)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We explore how teachers unions affect education production by comparing outcomes between districts allocating new tax revenue amidst collective bargaining negotiations and districts allocating tax revenue well before. Districts facing union pressure increase teacher salaries and benefits, spend down reserves, and experience no student achievement gains. Conversely, districts facing less pressure hire more teachers (instead of increasing compensation) and realize significant student achievement gains. We interpret these results as causal evidence of the negative impact of teacher rent seeking on education production, as the timing of district tax elections relative to collective bargaining appears to be as good as random.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pre-Publication Draft: &lt;a href=&#34;https://edworkingpapers.com/index.php/ai20-316&#34;&gt;EdWorkingPapers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Media: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.the74million.org/teachers-unions-lift-salaries-and-school-spending-research-shows-but-evidence-on-student-achievement-is-mixed/&#34;&gt;The 74&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
