<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Administrative Data | Corbin Miller</title>
    <link>https://corbinmiller.website/tags/administrative-data/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://corbinmiller.website/tags/administrative-data/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Administrative Data</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 09:04:42 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://corbinmiller.website/img/icon-192.png</url>
      <title>Administrative Data</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/tags/administrative-data/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Army Service in the All-Volunteer Era</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/project/army/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 09:04:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://corbinmiller.website/project/army/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The United States has relied exclusively on volunteers to serve in the military since July 1, 1973. Millions have since enlisted in the military, and these volunteers are disproportionately Black and from lower-income households, yet we know relatively little about whether enlistment improves or worsens their prospects. This paper links the universe of Army applicants between 1990 and 2011 to IRS data and exploits eligibility thresholds at the 31st and 50th percentile of the nationally-representative Armed Forces Qualifying Test (AFQT) in a regression discontinuity design to estimate the long-term, dynamic effects of Army enlistment on earnings and related outcomes. We show that Army service increases short-run earnings following Army application at both cutoffs. Enlistment increases long-run earnings at the higher cutoff, but at the lower cutoff long-run earnings gains are closer to zero and employment effects are negative, suggesting there are positive effects overall but that a small subset experience negative long term effects that a distributional analysis and findings on work-limiting disability confirm.  We also find that Army service increases college attendance, homeownership, marriage, and non-work-limiting disability compensation.  Finally, we uncover striking heterogeneity by race, with Black servicemembers experiencing larger long-term increases in earnings, marriage, and home-ownership at both cutoffs. We explore several potential channels for this heterogeneity including differential pre-application backgrounds and counterfactual opportunities, service experiences, and take-up of military benefits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employer-Sponsored Health Insurance Premiums and Income in US Tax Data</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/project/premiums/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 16:04:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://corbinmiller.website/project/premiums/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Currently available survey data does not capture important information about the distribution of employer-sponsored health insurance premiums in the US. We provide new evidence, based on administrative tax data, about the relationship of premiums to individual characteristics such as income. First, we demonstrate that premiums measured in the tax data are comparable to what we know from survey data. Then we show that those with higher incomes have more expensive policies. In fact, those in the top 10 percent of the income distribution account for 21 percent of total premiums. Even with these disparities, there is substantially less inequality in spending on ESI than in income overall.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employers and Disability Insurance: Evidence from Individual Tax Returns</title>
      <link>https://corbinmiller.website/project/employers_di/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2019 16:40:48 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://corbinmiller.website/project/employers_di/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we provide new evidence on the distribution of claims in the Social Security Disability Insurance (SSDI) program across employers and industries. We also relate SSDI claims to employer and employee wage premiums and discuss implications for measures of inequality. Our research makes use of the universe of individual tax returns for the period 2000-2018, which allows to develop measures of the incidence of SSDI claims for all U.S. firms and industries. We have two main findings. First, we find that there is substantial variation in SSDI claiming rates across firms and industries. Second, we find that there is a negative association between firm wage premiums and SSDI claiming rates.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
